[Music]
because I'm gonna keep this under five
minutes I'm gonna have to skip a lot of
the information if you want all that go
to the 55 minute video I will explain
all the terms I'll give you more
examples cover a bunch of different
topics you might be interested in like
fasting cold therapy saunas different
types of strength training etc okay but
for now here's the quick version of my
bulletproof BS detector step number one
you have to look at this spectrum I've
created and it's to determine where you
fall on it personally I can't tell you
which end is better generally people in
the purple are wrong less often but you
may identify more with the red end of
the spectrum or you may identify with
the blue in the spectrum it doesn't
necessarily matter because their
strengths the weak assists of both sides
and also being the middle you just have
to understand where you're not me
personally I'm about right here so keep
this in mind as we go through my BS
detectors that's how I'm generally
filtering things I'm a little more
conservative but not all the way to the
end so here's how this BS detector
actually works what you're trying to do
is determine the truth enos of something
thank you Stephen Colbert liked it like
that continuum I'm put in the bottom
there just two slides in a row two
different spectrums sorry but something
in the green would be as true as
something like one plus one equals two
alright so if something is over there
you're hundred-percent as confident as
you could get ever get that something is
true the other in a spectrum is
something that is the most ridiculous
thing you've ever heard there is zero
chance ever possibly true so all you're
doing with BS detection is trying to
figure out where whatever topic
character said it lies on this all the
way green all the way brown or is it
somewhere in the middle so here's how I
do that and figure out where something
lands I kind of view it as like ten
different categories of evidence now
before I get to further
I don't literally physically do this I'm
just filtering information constantly
and I'm adjusting where things land on
the spectrum when new information comes
in okay so I have about ten different
types of evidence that I consider once I
do that I go through the strengths of
each and give it us basically a mental
score one
so ten pipes one to 10 score it's a
hundred point scoring system then I make
a mental spider or radar plot and then
the strength of my conviction is Bank
them based on the strength the evidence
roughly okay so something that has a
score of a hundred out of 100 is gonna
be very green something with it score at
20 out of 100 it's probably gonna be
that yellowish brown it not always
doesn't always work like that but that's
basically the system so I'll give you
one example here what this might look
like so I've plotted all ten of my
evidence categories so I'll go through
three different examples to show you how
this could work so example number one
may look like something like that and I
may say hey there's really limited
information on anecdotes and experts
aren't enjoying it but there's some may
be acute mechanistic and molecular or
sellable research so maybe this isn't a
real thing but you're just over
interpreting cell culture research or
some molecular signaling pathway right a
different concept could look something
like this a lot of evidence in the
anecdote and from the experiments but
there's basically no science there's no
intervention studies doesn't make any TV
logical sense doesn't make any natural
sense and so I probably say this here
it's not worth my time yet now this is
not a case of something being brown this
is something yellow not worth my time
yet but I'm paying attention maybe as a
science involves and continues and it
changes all change where it is in the
spectrum so this is far from a brown but
just like the previous one was in a
green either because it had a lot more
points I still had some reservations
there thought it was probably being
over-interpret and then you can compare
this to the the fuchsia pinkish whatever
the hell color this thing is and you can
see it's getting points pretty much
across the board there yeah it's not
perfect snot 100 out of 100 but I would
probably at this point say all right it
works
people are trying it saying it works my
instincts say it works it makes natural
to a logical sense there's good training
data on it there's long-term data on it
as intervention when you give it to
people has an acute effect it probably
works of course I'm going to continue to
pay attention to the research but this
is probably getting pretty green in my
eyes so that's all I'm really doing and
that's how my system works now
a couple of things as we finish up this
is how people trick you number one
anyone can make things up that's always
true but that's not really a trick I
think you just have a liar on your hands
but number two and three are the ones
that confuse people so number two here
they don't divulge where they're at in
that spectrum so I'm fine with gurus and
hackers and people like that you just
got to tell me that your barrier for
being convinced is very very low and you
run more on instinct and you run more on
things like it makes natural sense to
you or feeling logical sense that's fine
does somebody know where you're at
there's a difference between your
opinion and the evidence and the problem
only happens when people conflate the
two right so if you're just saying hey
based on your experience in the field or
your gut instinct you think this is a
good idea I'm totally fine with that
just don't tell me the science is great
behind it when it's not or it's not very
expansive or same problem inferior on
the other the spectrum by the way all
that doesn't work why cuz it's not an
RCT behind it no that's not oh you're a
blue person okay fine I may have a
different level of confidence this kind
of leads into number three here which is
we have that mismatch of conviction
between evidence strength and this is
what happens when we create a zel it's
an ideal ox right so they see one piece
of information in one area and they
think the whole world should do that and
there's no other option and it's not
that they're wrong there's a work but
they're way too convinced and they're
not generally helping people because
they believe in it too much and what
they're really doing there is their
cherry-picking or misrepresenting the
well-roundedness of the evidence so if
there's strong anecdotal evidence and
there's strong molecular evidence it's
fine just say so but if it doesn't make
any dissents anywhere else
you should also acknowledge that part
hey there's good items here in here so
I'm really excited about this I think
this is gonna be something really great
that's very different than saying oh
this 100% work you guys are all idiots
if you don't believe it that's the trick
right
it can sound very convincing when they
cherry pick which categories to pick
from and how many and how deep to go in
in each category so you can see a whole
bunch of final reminders here that we're
not gonna have time to get into but
these are some things you need to
consider in a read on your own when you
go to apply this system
does actually make a ton of sense I'll
go into a lot of these examples or you
can google some of them but just
remember at the very end here being
wrong that's totally fine it's okay just
don't misrepresent your evidence that's
where people really get pissed for the
most part they feel lied to and feel
like you're trying to cheat them and
like I said I do have more examples in
the 55 minute version and I'll go
through a lot of categories that you
might find interesting
so hopefully you appreciate this video
and this is helping you a little bit in
the process and for the record if you
did enjoy this I know my wife's gonna
yell at you because it's actually the
second take this video and the first
time I said that she got mad and yelled
but what I'd like you to do instead of
donating to my patreon or sharing this
just go ahead and tell Miss Natasha Beck
that my appearance looks fine and the
quality of my information is more
important than my physical appearance
and she should love me either way which
she probably does anymore cuz I haven't
shaved in weeks all right thanks a lot
hope you enjoy